so we were on the subject of emptiness
and we were talking about
the emptiness of a pen and we were
asking well
how the heck is emptiness going to help
me you know
so if understanding emptiness is
important then then
what does it do for me how can it help
me get the things i want be in the
relationships i want
help other people why why should
understanding the pen
help me and other people so we were just
talking about how the pen is
like a blank movie screen the emptiness
of the pen
means that the pen is like a blank white
movie screen and then we said that if a
dog came in the room and they looked at
the same object
they might see something that they would
like to chew on and if a human
comes in the room and looks at the very
same thing
they will see a pen and they will see it
as something to write with
so we concluded that the pen must be
coming
this way and the pen is not coming this
way
if it were coming this way then the dog
would see a pen also or else i would
want to chew it
which i do sometimes uh
so then we talked about is it voluntary
what my mind is doing you see
is it if my mind is somehow
uh putting an image of a pen on this
thing if my mind if something is coming
out of my mind
and making me see a pen laying a pen
on this object if that's coming from my
own mind
is it voluntary is it something i can
just choose to do you see because then
things would be exciting
and and that's the idea of positive
thinking and just be positive
be happy uh and then things will change
you see
you can call it wishing you can call it
wanting
you can call it positive thinking you
can call it praying it doesn't matter
can i just close my eyes if the pen runs
out of ink
since the pen is coming from me can i
just close my eyes
and wish more ink more ink more ink if
i'm just
positive if i think positively
will the problems in my life change will
my boss become a nicer person
will my husband stop complaining you see
that i mean if i'm just
positive if i wish that things were
different
since they're coming from me then then
shouldn't that be possible and then we
did an experiment and we closed our eyes
and
we wished that the pen had ink and and
it didn't get inked just because
we wanted it so we can conclude that the
pen is coming from me
whether it has ink or not is coming from
me
but it's not something voluntary i can't
control the process
in the present moment can i control it
in the future you see i mean can i
can i make things happen even if i can't
wish things
into being one way or the other now is
there some process
is there some way in which i could
create the world i want and the
relationships i want
on the blank screen on the emptiness of
the world
which is which is filled in from my mind
like a movie cam
like a movie projector can i can i make
things happen
that i want to happen and i did
okay i did all right as my llama
challenged me to make a lot of money for
refugees
he challenged me to start a business in
new york it was the last thing i wanted
to do i have no interest in business
but he said as an experiment in the
understanding of emptiness
you see if you can sculpt
or create a future can you can you
can you make money using the principles
we taught you and we'll give the money
away we'll give it to poor people
okay and i did and he taught me how to
do it you see
you can create your future
you can create the world and
relationships that you want
because they are coming from your mind
but you have to understand how they're
coming from your mind
if you don't understand how they're
coming from your mind and you're just
trying to wish a relationship to be a
certain way
it's not going to work and you know that
because you try it
there's nobody who's having a bad
relationship that wants to have a bad
relationship
they're all wishing it would be good but
wishing doesn't change it
so how do you change it well then you
have to understand why is it you're
seeing a pen
what what makes your mind
project a picture of a pen
onto the subject and that picture is so
good that you can use it as a pen
all right we're talking we're not just
talking the mind makes up something
we're talking the mind
making up a thing which is so good that
it works
and you can you can write with it or or
money you can make money
you can make money that way okay so you
just have to we just have to understand
how to put an image in the mind that is
so strong
that it becomes reality how do you put
an image in the mind
that is so powerful that it becomes what
happens to you
next week you see and for that you need
to understand
seeds seeds in the mind we say that
if you understand how to plant a seed
within your own mind
then you can create the world you want
you can have the income you want that
the company he asked me to make is now
a quarter billion dollars 10 000 people
working there
and it was all created from seeds in the
mind
so how do you how do you put a seed in
the mind if we just give a small example
of a pen
and we understand how to put a seed in
your mind how to plant a seed in your
mind
then you can you can run with it you can
take it from there
you can you can create the relationship
you want you can improve your health or
your appearance
you can make money and you can change
the world i mean that's the whole point
isn't it you could
you could create a world that doesn't
have hunger or
war uh if you understand how to make a
pen
eventually you can work up to creating a
whole world okay which we call mandala
that's the meaning of mandala
right so how do you how would you create
a seed in your mind to see this object
as a pen and we know that for example
the dog we were talking about
doesn't have that scene in their mind so
they don't see this object as a pen
all right how do you put a seed in your
mind
that will enable you to see a pen that
will open in the mind
and then cause your mind to to lay a
picture of a pen on this
object which is so good that you can
write with it okay
i'll show you all right let's say i want
pens in the future
and then you can use it for dollars
later you can use it for
a boyfriend later you can use it for a
thinner body or stronger body you can
use it for whatever you want
or a world that doesn't have war in it
you see you can use it for anything
how do you plant a seed in the mind
for an object that you want so actually
you need another person
this this to plant a scene
in the mind requires other people you
need other people
so for a seed planter expert
other people become very valuable and
precious you need other people
it's you can plant a seed with yourself
but it's very
weak and very small you need other
people
with whom you can plant a seed so let's
say i want
pants next week in my future i would
like to have pens and again it could be
a boyfriend it could be a stronger body
it could be a million dollars it doesn't
matter
or a world that doesn't have war i i
want to see
something a week or two weeks from now
how do i put the seed in my mind that
will enable me to see that
so you look for someone who needs what
you want
you see let's say i need pens i want
pants
i would like to have pens in my world
next week or two weeks from now
so then i have to look around in my life
i need to find people who need what i
want you see
i need to find in this case someone who
wants a pin if i want money i have to
find people who
who desperately need money if i want a
new relationship
i have to find someone who wants a
relationship
if i want to create peace in the world
i have to find and help people create
peace
okay so in the case of a pen
i look around and i try to find someone
who needs a pen i'm very sensitive
to people who need a pen or i'm very
sensitive to people who
who are looking for a new relationship
when i spot one
i jump on it and i grab them and i say
you need a pen
they say yes i really need a pen right
now then
i take my favorite pen this happens to
be my favorite kind of pen
this kind of pen is hard to get it's
from japan
and i really like them so i i take my
favorite pen
and i say okay i understand you need a
pen
then i i slowly offered to them okay
my hand by the way my mind is watching
my hand right
i am watching one hand uh
with a pen that is approaching another
this is the other person's hand
and and my mind is like a video camera
my mind is watching my hand
go down to the other person's head
and then there's a very crucial moment
when the pen
touches the other person's hand and i
and with the thought that i would like
them to have the pen
because they need the pen right now
watch i release the pen i i let go
and that's called giving that action
that moment of of thinking they need
this thing
and i will give it to them and you
release you hold on your own pen
after you release it it's not yours
anymore it becomes theirs
it is a very profound moment
mind mind mind mind
yours when i go from mine
to yours when i think this pen is no
longer mine
now this pen is yours that that
perception that thought plants a seed in
my mind
for pen all right that's cool that's
really cool
that moment of thought puts a seed
for a pen in my mind then then you
should ask me a question you should say
what's the point you know uh you already
have a pen
why why why go give a pen
if you're putting a seat in your mind
for a pen why not just keep the pen you
see
that that means you don't really
understand the nature of seeds seeds are
amazing
think about the seed which created your
body okay there was a little tiny
thing looks like a tadpole a sperm from
your father
and then there was a little thing that
looks like a donut or i don't know what
it looks like
it's the egg from your mother right and
the red egg and the white sponge
and then they they meet it's only a few
self
meet each other at your conception
and then for 50 60
70 years your body is sustained by those
two cells few cells those seeds
those two seeds are strong enough they
have some
amazing miraculous power within the two
seas
that for 50 60 70 years
all of the cells of your body trillions
upon trillions of cells
even at any given moment are created
from the two
the same is true of mental seeds okay
don't think it's less than that
putting inside of my mind a single seed
for a pen okay i give somebody a pen
when i release the pen a single seed is
planted within my mind
and then you have to get the feeling of
how strong that is
that seed will grow in the same way that
an acorn grows into an oak tree
it's not that i get one pen back
in my life by offering someone else a
pen
when i offer someone else a pen when i
offer someone else a pen
and i and a single seed is planted in my
mind
then that multiplies in the in the
subconscious over time
that single seed multiplies constantly
and then many many pens will come back
to me you see because pens don't come
back to me
it's that seeds are planted in my mind
to see an object as a pen
and then that happens over and over
again that that seed will be repeated
over and over again okay so pens are not
so important
but what about if you wanted a
relationship
that was sustained the relationship
wouldn't go through that normal thing
where it's really nice in the beginning
and then it starts to go downhill if you
understood the seeds
which created a relationship then you
could make a relationship
which got better every year and sweeter
every year
so let's talk about that next